Ajay Kale

Data Scientist

CONTACT

Brentwood TN



(615) 573-6433





in ajaykale

PROFILE

An accomplished IT Professional with over 2 decades of experience in full life cycle design, development and software architecture. Proficient in utilizing advanced statistical methods and machine learning algorithms to extract meaningful insights from complex data sets.

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST APPRENTICE

SEPT 2022 - PRESENT

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Nashville TN

Intensive part-time bootcamp focusing on software engineering skills required to do data science. Worked on real-world datasets and problems from various domains like healthcare, retails and government.

- Analyzed and processed complex data sets using advanced querying
- Performed exploratory data analysis to understand relationships. opportunities to influence outcome using Python and R
- Performed webscraping and used APIs to gather data
- Creating meaningful data visualizations using matplotlib, Seaborn and R Shiny library
- Interpret the model that are being generated
- Conducting advanced statistical analysis to determine trends and significant data relationships.
- Working with Git/GitHub for version control
- Performed network analysis on graph data using Neo4j

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

OCT 2016 - PRESENT

PILLSBURY WINTHROP SHAW PITMAN NASHVILLE TN

Pillsbury Winthrop Shaw Pittman is a full-service, global law firm with an industry focus on the technology & life sciences, energy, financial, and real estate & construction sectors.

Responsibilities

- Designing and developing web applications in C#, asp.Net/Core, Microsoft Blazor, MVC, SharePoint, Angular
- Preparing detailed technical specifications
- Designing, creating databases, Tables, Writing Stored procedures
- Developing/consuming REST APIs
- Reverse engineering existing applications and developing them in .Net/Sharepoint
- Migrating databases to SQL Server
- Troubleshooting and supporting existing applications
- Performing code merges in version control
- Responsible for builds and deployments

EDUCATION

- Masters Degree in Management Science
- Bachelors Degree in Mechanical Engineering

SKILLS

- Python (NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, Scikit learn)
- R (Plotly, Shiny)
- SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- Git/GitHub/SVN/TFS
- ASP.Net, C#, MVC, JSON, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL LEAD

AFFINION GROUP NASHVILLE TN OCT 2013 – SEPT 2016

SENIOR .NET DEVELOPER

CERES TERMINALS INC NASHVILLE TN SEPT 2010 – SEPT 2013